【音乐】上一节我们学习路由
[Music]
in the last section our study of routing was primarily theoretical took a look
主要是理论性的研究了路由算法
集中式和分布式计算最小成本路径
at routing algorithms both centralized and distributed for computing minimum cost paths from source
本节中的源到目的地，下一节我们将进行
to destination in this section and the next we're going to look at putting
考虑将这些原则付诸实践，我将开始
these principles into practice i'm going to start by looking at two particular considerations
着眼于规模和自主权的两个特定考虑因素
这对于将这些原则付诸实践非常重要
scale and autonomy that are really important in putting these principles into practice for
为了规模，当字面上存在时，我们如何进行路由
scale how do we do routing when
for scale how do we do routing when
为了规模，当字面上存在时，我们如何进行路由
there are literally billions of endpoints to be routed to autonomy has to do
要路由到自治的数十亿端点与允许网络有关
经理和操作员选择路由的完成方式
there are literally billions of endpoints to be routed to autonomy has to do
with allowing network managers and operators to choose how routing's done both within their
在他们自己的网络内以及如何路由
对远程网络也完成了我们将介绍两个路由
own network and how routing is done to distant networks as well we're going
此处的协议开放最短路径优先 ospf 路由
to cover two routing protocols here the open shortest path first ospf routing algorithm
控制路由的算法路由协议
在一个网络中，我们还将介绍
to cover two routing protocols here the open shortest path first ospf routing algorithm
routing protocol for controlling routing within a network then we're also going to cover
在下一节中，边界网关协议 bgp 用于
in the following section the border gateway protocol bgp for routing among networks so
在网络之间路由，所以我们为什么不得到
开始，我们将开始研究这个问题
why don't we get started and we're going to start with looking at this
规模和自治我们迄今为止对路由算法的研究
issue of scale and also autonomy our study of routing algorithms so far has
已经非常理想化了我们已经考虑了网络
been pretty idealized we've considered the network as sort of a sea of indistinguishable
就像一片难以区分的路由器的海洋
通过链接连接我们只是想找到最短路径
been pretty idealized we've considered the network as sort of a sea of indistinguishable
routers that were connected by links we simply wanted to find a shortest path
从源路由器到目的路由器
from a source router to a destination
router
实际上，事情比那要复杂一点
well in practice things are a little bit
more complicated than that
它们主要因规模问题而变得复杂
and they're complicated primarily by the
issue of scale
我们如何能够路由到数十亿个 n 主机和数百个
how is it that we can route to literally
billions of n-hosts and hundreds of
数以千计的目标网络，如果你认为
thousands
of destination networks if you think
关于它，路由器的转发表不可能容纳十亿
about it a router's forwarding table
couldn't possibly hold a billion
转发所有目标主机的条目
forwarding entries for all of the
destination hosts
类似地，当我们考虑路由算法交换时
and similarly when we think about a
routing algorithm exchanging
距离向量或链接状态信息字面上与
distance vector or link state
information literally with
数以百万计的其他实体是不可扩展的，用完所有的弯曲
millions of other entities just isn't
scalable use up all the bend within the
网络仅用于控制目的
network
just for control purposes
然后是自治的问题，这可能会少一点
and then there's the issue of autonomy
and this might be a little less
显然，请记住互联网是一个由网络组成的网络，
obvious remember the internet is a
network of networks and
每个网络都有一个所有者运营商到什么程度
each network has an owner operator to
what extent
该网络所有者运营商可以或应该是
can or should that network owner
operator be
告诉如何路由流量 网络相对于它的自主权
told how to route traffic what autonomy
does a network have with respect to its
路由我们会看到互联网方法是
routing
we'll see that the internet approach is
首先网络可以选择使用任何东西
twofold first
a network can choose to use whatever
它在自己的网络中想要的路由协议，其次是一个
routing protocol it wants
in its own network and secondly a
网络将能够控制来自其客户网络的流量
network will be able to control how
traffic from its customer networks
路由到目的地以及它如何作为网络
is routed towards a destination and how
it as a network
路由它承载的由其他网络发送给它的流量
routes traffic that it carries that's
sent to it by other networks
好吧，让我们从缩放问题开始
well let's begin with the issue of
scaling
互联网扩展路由的方法始于
the internet approach to scaling routing
begins with the notion of
将路由器聚合到网络或有时称为的区域中
aggregating routers into networks or
into regions that are sometimes called
自治系统或域，正如我们将看到的
autonomous systems or domains and as
we'll see
基本上有两种类型的路由 有用于路由的路由协议
there's basically two types of routing
there's routing protocols for routing
在一个域内，并且有路由协议
within a domain
and there are routing protocols for
域之间的路由，正如我们将看到的那样
routing among domains
and as we'll see there are different
每个协议，让我们从概念开始
protocols for each
and let's start with the notion of
在自治系统内的网络内路由，这称为
routing within a network within
an autonomous system this is known as
域内路由和中继域内
intra
domain routing and in in trunk domain
路由域内的所有路由器
routing
all routers within the domain within the
网络内的自治系统都在执行相同的路由
autonomous system within the network
are all executing the same routing
协议不同但网络不同
protocols
but different networks different
自治系统可以选择自己的域内路由协议
autonomous systems can choose
their own intra domain routing protocol
正如我们将看到的每个自治系统的边缘
and as we'll see the edge of every
autonomous system
是一种特殊类型的路由器，称为网关
is a specialized type of router known as
a gateway
将一个自治系统连接到另一个
that will connect one autonomous system
to another
然后就是所谓的内部
and then there's inter-as otherwise
known as
自治系统间路由的域间路由
inter domain routing for routing among
autonomous systems
这里网络的网关将执行域间路由
here a network's gateway is going to
perform inter domain routing
以及参与域内路由
as well as participate in intra domain
routing
在它自己的自治系统中，这是一个具有三个自治系统的网络
within its own autonomous system here's
a network with three autonomous systems
as1 as2 和 as3 三个相互连接的网络
as1 as2 and as3
three interconnected networks each as
每个都有自己的域内路由协议
has its own
intra-domain routing protocol each as
可以使用不同的域内路由协议
could use a
different intra-domain routing protocol
这对其他驴来说并不重要，因为它是
it doesn't really matter
to the other asses since that as is
只是在域内路由，我们在这里看到了内部
just routing within intra-domain and we
see here the inter
自治系统路由协议，负责在
autonomous system routing protocol
that's responsible for routing between
域之间的域内路由
and
among domains the intra domain routing
协议将用于填充路由器的转发表
protocol will be used to populate
a router's forwarding table for
网络内的目的地，但目的地的流量呢？
destinations within the network
but what about traffic destined to
在网络之外，这里是域间的域间
outside the network
it's here that the inter-as inter-domain
路由协议和一些内部路由
routing protocol
and a bit of the intra-as routing
协议将用于填充路由器的转发表
protocol will be used to populate a
router's forwarding table
对于网络外的目的地，但让我们从路由和
for destinations outside the network but
let's start with the case of routing and
转发到目的地，因为那里更容易
forwarding to destinations within
the as since that's a bit easier there
只有三个域内路由协议
have only been
three intra domain routing protocols
在实践中已经采用的第一个是路由信息
that have been adopted in practice
the first is the routing information
简单地称为 rip rip 的协议是在 1980 年代早期发明的，并且
protocol simply known as rip rip
was invented in the early 1980s and
在 RFC 1723 中标准化，这是一个经典的距离向量
standardized in rfc
1723 it's a classic distance vector
每 30 次定期交换距离矢量协议的协议
protocol where distance vector protocols
are exchanged periodically every 30
秒 它在 80 年代 90 年代被广泛使用
seconds
it was used widely in the 80s the 90s
并进入 oos 但 rip 最终被超越
and into the oos
but rip was eventually overtaken as an
开放最短路径优先或ospf的域内路由协议  ospf 是使用 dijkstra 算法的经典链路状态协议
intra-domain routing protocol
by the open shortest path first or ospf
开放最短路径优先或ospf的域内路由协议  ospf 是使用 dijkstra 算法的经典链路状态协议
protocol ospf is a classic link state
protocol that uses dijkstra's algorithm
为了计算最短路径，有一个称为 isis 的相关协议
to compute shortest paths
there's a related protocol known as isis
中间系统到中间系统路由
intermediate system to intermediate
system routing that's
非常相似，几乎与 ospf 相同，但由国际标准化
very similar almost identical to ospf
but standardized by the international
标准组织 iso 而不是 ietf 并且只是一个
standards organization
iso rather than the ietf and in just a
其次，我们要仔细看看
second we're going to take a little bit
closer look
在 ospf 因为现在它是最
at ospf because really right now it's
the most
在实践中广泛部署的域内路由协议
widely deployed intra domain routing
protocol in practice
第三个常用的内部路由协议
the third commonly deployed intra-as
routing protocol
eigrp 是增强型内部网关路由协议吗
is eigrp the enhanced interior gateway
routing protocol
它也是基于距离向量的，实际上它是
it's also distance vector based and
actually it was
几十年来，您实际上无法在 cisco 内部专有
formerly proprietary within cisco for
decades you couldn't actually
弄清楚 eigrp 到底是什么，但是在 2013 年 cisco 开源了 eigrp
figure out exactly what was in eigrp
however in 2013 cisco open sourced eigrp
它变成了一个开放的协议 现在让我们来看看 ospf
and it became an open protocol now let's
take a look at the ospf
开放最短路径优先路由协议
open shortest path first routing
protocol
on ospf 代表开放意味着规范
on ospf stands for open meaning that the
specifications
公开可用的 ospf 是每个路由器都在使用的经典链路状态协议
publicly available ospf is a classic
link state protocol each router is going
泛滥 ospf 链接状态广告
to flood ospf
link state advertisements across the
每个 ospf 路由器将要访问的整个自治系统
entire autonomous system
that is each ospf router is going to
关于每个附加的洪水信息
flood
information about each of its attached
将传播到自治中的所有其他路由器的链接
links that will propagate to
all other routers in the autonomous
系统等在一个经典的链接状态算法
system and so
as in a classic link state algorithm
每个路由器都有完整的拓扑信息 ospf 然后使用
each router has
full topology information ospf then uses
计算每个转发表的类似 dijkstra 的算法
dijkstra-like algorithm to compute each
forwarding table
多个链路成本指标是可能的 可用带宽量
multiple link cost metrics are possible
the amount of bandwidth available the
与链路相关的延迟是链路成本度量的两个示例
delay associated with the link are two
examples of link cost metrics
最后是 ospf 中的最新创新之一
and finally one of the most recent
innovations in ospf
真正需要的创新是所有 ospf 消息
really a needed innovation is that all
ospf messages
经过身份验证的 ospf 也可以在所谓的层次结构中运行
are authenticated ospf can also
operate in what's called a hierarchical
模式 ospf 层次结构有两个级别，您可以在本地区域
mode ospf hierarchies have
two levels there's a local area you can
在图中看到这里的三个区域区域一二和三
see here in the figure
three areas area one two and three as
以及骨干和岭州广告作为
well as a backbone
and ling state advertisements as part of
经典的链接状态算法现在只会被淹没在
the classic link state algorithm
are now only going to be flooded within
一个区域或主干内，这样您就可以看到如何
an area
or within a backbone so you can see how
这种层次结构将限制信息量
this hierarchical structure is going to
scope the amount of information that
在整个路由器之间流动
flows
among the routers in the entire
分层网络每个节点都会有详细的
hierarchical network
each node is going to have detailed
有关其区域内或内部的完整拓扑的信息
information about the
full topology within its area or within
它的骨干所以问题是你怎么知道
its backbone
so the question is how do you know how
路由到不属于您的其他节点
to route to
other nodes that are not part of your
区域或不在主干中 这是区域边界的作用
area or not in the backbone
this is the role of the area border
路由器区域边界路由器将汇总距离
routers an area border router is going
to summarize distances
到自己区域内的其他目的地，并将其通告给其他节点
to other destinations in its own area
and advertise this to other nodes in the
区域中的本地路由器正在运行的骨干网
backbone
the local routers in an area are going
就像他们将要执行的经典链接状态算法一样执行
to perform just like classic
link state algorithms they're going to
他们将要计算的区域内的洪水链接状态信息
flood link state information
within the area they're going to compute
在区域内路由，他们将转发数据包
routing within the area
and they're going to forward packets
需要到区域外的区域边界路由器
that need to go outside the area
to the area border router in the
骨干网 我们看到了两种类型的路由器 我们看到了一个边界
backbone we see
two types of routers we see a boundary
将这个分层 ospf 网络连接到更大的路由器
router that's going to connect this
hierarchical ospf network to the larger
外部世界连接到其他自治系统，然后在
outside world to connect to other
autonomous systems and then within the
骨干 有骨干路由器将运行 ospf 他们将要
backbone there are backbone routers that
are going to run ospf they're going to
泛洪链路状态信息，但只会在骨干网内这样做
flood link state information but will do
so only within the backbone
好吧，这结束了我们关于实践的两个部分中的第一部分
well that wraps up the first of our two
sections on the practice of
我们看到了互联网路由协议的问题
internet routing protocols we saw how
the issues of
规模和自主性是设计中真正重要的考虑因素
scale and autonomy are really important
considerations in designing
互联网路由是如何工作的 我们看了一下
how internet routing works we took a
look at one
三域路由协议中开放最短路径优先
in tri domain routing protocol the open
shortest path first
当今互联网上广泛使用的 ospf 协议
ospf protocol that's widely used in the
internet today
在下一节中，我们将看看国际米兰
coming up in the next section we're
going to take a look at an inter
域路由协议边界网关协议
domain routing protocol the border
gateway protocol
bgp 只有一种域间路由协议
bgp there's only one inter domain
routing protocol
在互联网中使用，因此 bgp 有时被称为
in use in the internet and for that
reason bgp is sometimes referred to as
将互联网连接在一起的粘合剂，因为
the glue
that holds the internet together because
bgp 决定路由是如何完成的
it's bgp
that determines how routing is done
在独立的自治系统之间 你
among  separate autonomous systems